var interprets = [
  /*   { question: "go to + 장소", answer: "~에 가다" },
    { question: "go on + 여행", answer: "~를 가다" }, */
  /*   { question: "go v-ing", answer: "~하러가다" }, */
  { question: "시간 + long", answer: "~짜리의, ~길이의" },
  { question: "by + 명사", answer: "~에 의해서, ~까지" },
  /*   { question: "make a decision", answer: "결정을 내리다" }, */
  /*   { question: "help + 목적어 + to V", answer: "목적어가 ~하는것을 돕다." },
    { question: "by oneself(강조)", answer: "혼자서(혼자 있음을 강조)" },
    { question: "on one's own", answer: "혼자서" },
    { question: "for oneself(강조)", answer: "스스로(스스로의 힘을 강조)" },
    { question: "make a deal", answer: "거래를 하다." },
    { question: "make a contract", answer: "계약을 맺다" },
    { question: "make a choice", answer: "선택을 하다" },
    { question: "make an exception", answer: "예외를 두다" },
    { question: "make a concession", answer: "양보를 하다" }, */
  { question: "in itself", answer: "그 자체로" },
  /*   { question: "available + 사람", answer: "시간이 있는" },
    { question: "available + 사물", answer: "이용 가능한" }, */
  /*   { question: "interest rate", answer: "이자율, 금리" }, */
  /*   { question: "be + pp", answer: "~ 되다" }, */
  /*   { question: "pay for", answer: "지불하다" },
    { question: "be + 감정 형용사 + v", answer: "~해서 ~하다" },
    { question: "refer to", answer: "~를 참조하다" },
    { question: "per month", answer: "달하다" },
    { question: "take place", answer: "열리다." }, */
  /*   { question: "respond to", answer: "~에 응답하다" }, */
  /*   { question: "from [A] to [B](범위)", answer: "A에서 B까지(시간,장소)" },
    { question: "from [A] until [B]", answer: "A에서 B까지 (시간) " },
    //  { question: "the number of", answer: "~의 숫자" },
    { question: "across + 명사", answer: "~를 가로질러, ~전역에" },
    { question: "can apply for", answer: "~에 지원하다" },
    { question: "quite + a/an + 형 + 명", answer: "꽤 형한명사" }, */

  // [2주차]
  /*   { question: "(~등을)gose on", answer: "(여행등을)가다" },
    { question: "by + 교통수단", answer: "~를 타고" },
    { question: "greatful for", answer: "~에 대해 감사하는" },
    { question: "depart for", answer: "~로 출발하다" },
    { question: "header for", answer: "~로 가다, 향하다" },
    { question: "next to", answer: "~옆에" },
    { question: "not A But B", answer: "A가 아니라 B" },
    { question: "if/whether + 완전한 문장", answer: "~인지 아닌지" },
    { question: "right to-v", answer: "~할 권리" },
    { question: "ask for", answer: "~을 요청하다" },
    { question: "invest in", answer: "~에 투자하다" },
    { question: "take a class", answer: "수업을 듣다" },
    { question: "take an exam", answer: "시험을 보다" },
    { question: "take a 물건", answer: "가지고 가다" },
    { question: "take a 시간", answer: "~이 걸리다" },
    { question: "take a advantage of", answer: "~을 이용하다" },
    { question: "(up)on request", answer: "요청시에" },
    { question: "(up)on arrival", answer: "도착하는 즉시" },
    { question: "survey", answer: "설문조사" },
    { question: "an hour and half", answer: "1시간 30분" },
    { question: "half an hour", answer: "30분" },
    { question: "take off", answer: "~을 벗다" },
    { question: "had better + 동사원형", answer: "~하는것이 좋다" },
    { question: "take a day off", answer: "하루쉬다" },
    { question: "if절 내 should", answer: "혹시라도" },
    { question: "hand in", answer: "~을 제출하다" },
    { question: "on time", answer: "제시간에" },
    { question: "in time", answer: "늦지 않게" },
    { question: "on schedule", answer: "일정대로" },
    { question: "drop by", answer: "~에 들르다" },
    { question: "stop by", answer: "~(잠시)들르다" },
    { question: "put off", answer: "(일정등을)연기하다" },
    { question: "get along", answer: "(사람들과)지내다" }, */
  { question: "call for", answer: "~을 요구하다" },
  { question: "call a meeting", answer: "회의를 소집하다" },
  { question: "don't have to-v", answer: "~할 필요가 없다" },
  { question: "could have p.p.", answer: "~할 수도 있었다." },
  { question: "should have p.p.", answer: "~했어야 했다(그러지 않음)" },
  { question: "shouldn't have p.p.", answer: "~하지 말았어야 했다" },
  { question: "must have p.p.", answer: "~했음에 틀림없다" },
  { question: "be + sure", answer: "~라고 확신하다" },
  { question: "in + 기간", answer: "~후애" },
  { question: "within + 기간", answer: "~내에" },
  { question: "leave of absence", answer: "휴가" },
  { question: "on 요일s", answer: "~마다" },
  { question: "a growing number of +  복수명사", answer: "점점 더 많은 ~" },
  { question: "file a complaint", answer: "항의를 제기하다" },
  // 2024-03-11
  { question: "deliver a lecture", answer: "강의를 하다" },
  { question: "lay off", answer: "해고하다" },
  { question: "be made of", answer: "~로 만들어지다" },
  { question: "be used to 명사", answer: "~에 익숙하다" },
  { question: "take place", answer: "열리다" },
  { question: "hold", answer: "열다" },
  { question: "be known for", answer: "~로 유명하다" },
  { question: "be famous for", answer: "~로 유명하다" },
  { question: "place an order", answer: "주문하다" },
  { question: "yours = your + 명사", answer: "너의 것" },
  { question: "travel agency", answer: "여행사" },
  { question: "travel arrangement", answer: "여행" },
  { question: "travel itinerary", answer: "여행 일정표" },
  { question: "work long hours", answer: "장시간 일하다" },
  { question: "work a night shift", answer: "야간 근무를 하다" },
  { question: "in need to", answer: "~를 필요로 하는" },
  { question: "in order to-v", answer: "~하기 위해서" },
  { question: "be busy -ing", answer: "~하느라 바쁘다" },
  { question: "be worth -ing", answer: "~할 가치가 있다" },
  { question: "feel like -ing", answer: "~하고 싶다" },
  { question: "have difficulty/trouble -ing", answer: "~하는데 어려움을 겪다" },
  { question: "keep -ing", answer: "계속 ~하다" },
  { question: "be free to-v", answer: "자유롭게 하다, ~해도 된다" },
  { question: "please feel free to-v", answer: "자유롭게 ~하세요" },

  // 2024-03-25(중요!!)
  { question: "as", answer: "~할때, ~함에 따라, ~때문에" },
  { question: "as soon as", answer: "~하자마자" },
  { question: "while", answer: "~하는 동안, ~한 반면에" },
  { question: "unless", answer: "만약 ~하지 않는다면" },
  { question: "once", answer: "일단 ~하면" },
  { question: "as long as", answer: "~하는 한" },
  { question: "although", answer: "비록 ~하지만" },
  { question: "though", answer: "비록 ~하지만" },
  { question: "even though", answer: "비록 ~하지만" },
  { question: "even if", answer: "비록 ~하지만" },
  { question: "whereas", answer: "~한 반면에" },
  { question: "now that", answer: "이제 ~니까" },
  { question: "in that", answer: "~라는 점에서" },
  { question: "so that", answer: "~하기 위해서" },
  { question: "in order that ", answer: "~하기 위해서" },

  // 2024-03-26
  { question: "paid vacation", answer: "유급휴가" },
  { question: "paid leave", answer: "유급휴가" },
  { question: "inform A or B", answer: "A에게 B를 알리다" },
  { question: "look good on", answer: "~에게 어울리다" },
  { question: "turn out to be ~", answer: "~인것으로 밝혀지다" },
  { question: "win the prize", answer: "상을 받다" },

  // 2024-03-26
  { question: "work going", answer: "일을 하다" },
  { question: "go to work", answer: "출근하다" },
  { question: "get to work", answer: "회사에 도착하다" },

  // 2024-03-28
  { question: "stand in for ~", answer: "~을 대신하다" },
  { question: "fill in for ~", answer: "~을 대신하다" },
  { question: "pass by", answer: "지나가다" },
  { question: "be sick of", answer: "~에 실증이 나다" },
  { question: "free of charge", answer: "무료로" },
  { question: "place an emphasis on ~", answer: "~을 강조하다" },

  //듣기2
  { question: "I'm not sure", answer: "잘 모르겠어요" },
  { question: "I have no idea", answer: "전혀 모르겠어요" },
  { question: "Let me check", answer: "확인해볼게요" },
  { question: "I'll have to check", answer: "확인해봐야 할 거에요" },
  { question: "I'll take a look", answer: "한 번 볼게요" },
  { question: "Ask A", answer: "A에게 물어보라" },
  { question: "Check with B", answer: "B에게 확인해보세요" },
  { question: "This 아/점/저", answer: "오늘 아/점/저에요" },
  { question: "I'd be happy to", answer: "기꺼이요" },
  { question: "Certainly", answer: "그럼요" },
  { question: "I'll do now", answer: "지금 할게요" },
  { question: "I'll take care of it", answer: "제가 처리할게요" },
  { question: "I'm afraid not", answer: "유감이지만 안되요" },
  { question: "in 숫자 minutes", answer: "숫자분 후에요" },
  { question: "It's not my decision", answer: "그건 제 결정사항이 아니에요" },
  { question: "(주어) (동사) not in charge of it", answer: "그것을 담당하지 않아요" },
  { question: "It depends on ~", answer: "~에 달려있어요(다른 요소에 따라 달라짐)" },
  { question: "Let's ~", answer: "~합시다" },
  { question: "Why don't we ~", answer: "~하는게 어때요?" },
  { question: "I suggest ~", answer: "저는 ~제안해요" },
  { question: "Could / Would you ~?", answer: "~해주시겠어요?" },
  { question: "Would you mind ~?", answer: "~해주시겠어요?" },
  { question: "I need you to ~", answer: "~해주세요", },

  // { question: "", answer: "" },
];

// -------------------------- 해석 end --------------------------